PERSONAL INFORMATION

Mario Romano

- ₹50C Gascony Avenue, NW6 4NE, London
- **+447577282762**
- mario.romano83@gmail.com
- in http://www.linkedin.com/pub/mario-romano/14/6a7/51a

Sex Male | Date of birth 16 September 1983 | Nationality Italian

SUMMARY AND KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS

My fields of expertise are: Java, Javascript, Android, Html, Asp and C++. I have been working for fourth years at Accenture Technology Solutions as Analyst Developer During my career at Accenture Technology Solutions I have reached significant achievements that granted me a bright career inside this company. Since September 2012 I work in London. In London I have improved my knowledge on TDD, REST and Clean Coding practice working with 2 java champions , also I had a chance to work on a few projects javascript object oriented. Currently I'm working in Alfresco where I'm Tech Lead of the London Office.

Developing is not just a job for me, I spend my spare time learning new codes every day. At the moment my efforts go towards Android, Java and javascript oo.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

September 2002 to March 2007 Bachelor's degree: Computer Science and Engineering.

University: University of Naples Federico II, Italy.

Grade: 88/110

Thesis and Internship: Gaming, Social Network Integration.

Languages: Java, JavaEE Javascript, Node.js, Android, HTML, CSS, SQL.

Frameworks: Spring, Guava, Dropwizard, Backbone, Angular, Hibernate, Bootstrap.

Databases: Mysql, Oracle, H2, MongoDB.

Build Tools: Maven, Ant, Gradle.

Practices: SCRUM, Agile, Tribe, TDD, Clean coding, Pair programming, Continuous delivery.

Architectures: Microservices, Single Page Application, REST, Client/Server.

IDE: Eclipse, IntelliJ, Android Studio.

Version control: Git , Clear case.

Cloud application platform: Heroku, AWS, Parse.

Others: Redis, Riak, Bower, Grunt, Npm, Node, Handlebar, Jenkins, Guice.

Operating systems: Linux , Osx, Windows.

WORK EXPERIENCE

May 2015 to Cuurent Job Employer: Alfresco Role: Team Lead Projects: Activiti BPM

Responsibilities:

- Key contributor in an on-going project to develop a new SPA.
- Integrate BPM and ECM.
- Responsible for the design and implementation of new functionalities for the FE/BE application.
- Build a new team.
- Actively involved in interviewing and hiring of new team

members.

Technologies: java EE, spring, mysql, riak, javascript, css, html, bootstrap, angular, handlebar, grunt, bower, npm, json, continuous delivery.

Tools: eclipse, git, jenkins.

Practices: Scrum, TDD, Clean coding.

August 2013 to May 2015 Employer: Workshare

Role: Senior full stack developer

Projects: Professional (file sharing collaboration, similar to dropbox)

Responsibilities:

- Key contributor in an on-going project to develop a new CMS capable of handling large and ever increasing content volumes, bulding a new microservices architecture.
- Responsible for the design and implementation of new functionalities for the FE/BE application.
- Effectively mentored the Junior Developer assigned to the team.
- Actively involved in interviewing and hiring of new team members.

Technologies: java EE, microservices, guava guice, redis, mysql, riak, javascript, css, html, bootstrap, backbone, handlebar, grunt, bower, npm, json.

Tools: eclipse, git, jenkins.

Practices: Scrum, Tribe, TDD, Clean coding.

February 2013 to August 2013 Employer: ITHR Consulting.
Role: Senior full stack developer.

Projects: MTD Internation Trading System. Practices: Scrum, TDD, Clean coding.

Responsibilities:

- Responsible for the design and implementation of new functionalities, writing code and conducting integration tests.
- Effectively mentored the Junior Developer assigned to the team, providing guidance and support resulting in an increase in productivity of 50%. Applied strong technical skills, expertly splitting complex problems and tasks into smaller parts to boost the Developer's confidence and optimise potential.
- Actively involved in interviewing and hiring of new team members.

Technologies: java EE, spring, velocity, javascript, jquery, bootstrap, html, css, apache.

Tools: eclipse, git, jenkins.

September 2012 to February 2013

Employer: ITHR Consulting.
Role: Senior software developer.
Projects: Vodafone Mobile Portal.

Responsibilities:

• Responsible for the design and implementation of new functionalities, writing code and conducting integration tests.

Personally fixed bugs.

Technologies: java EE, spring, velocity, javascript, jquery, bootstrap,

html, css, apache.

Tools: eclipse, git, jenkins.

Practices: Scrum, TDD, Clean coding.

March 20012 to August 2012 Employer: Accenture.

Role: Analyst /Software developer.

Projects: Eni Work Planning.

Responsibilities:

• Responsable of the FE and BE team (10 members).

- Effectively mentored the Junior Developer assigned to the team.
- Responsible for the design and implementation of new functionalities, writing code and conducting integration tests.
- Actively involved in interviewing and hiring of new team members.

Technologies: java EE, struts2, hibernate, log4j, sql, javascript, jquery, ajax, html, css, oracle, Apache.

Tools: eclipse, clear case, clear quest, soapUI.

September 2011 to March 2012

Employer: Accenture.

Role: Analyst / Software developer.

Projects: Smart Mobile Social Network.

Responsibilities:

- Responsable of the FE and BE team (10 members).
- Effectively mentored the Junior Developer assigned to the team.
- Responsible for the design and implementation of new functionalities, writing code and conducting integration tests.
- Actively involved in interviewing and hiring of new team members.

Technologies: android, javavascript, ajax, html, css, jquery, json, wak. Tools: android studio, clear case, clear quest.

October 2008 to September 2011

Employer: Accenture.

Role: Analyst /Software developer.

Projects: Telecom Italy Top Business.

Responsibilities:

- Responsible for the design and implementation of new functionalities, writing code and conducting integration tests.
- Effectively mentored the Junior Developer assigned to the team, providing guidance and support resulting in an increase in productivity of 50%. Applied strong technical skills, expertly splitting complex problems and tasks into smaller parts to boost the Developer's confidence and optimise potential.
- Actively involved in interviewing and hiring of new team members.

Technologies: java EE, struts2, hibernate, log4j, sql, javascript, jquery, ajax, html, css, oracle, Apache.

Tools: eclipse, clear case, clear quest, soapUI.

May 2008 to October 2008 Employer: Accenture.
Role: Software developer.
Projects: Generali Insurance.

Responsibilities:

• Personally fixed bugs and implemented improvement features using Java and J2EE on a large scale project.

Technologies: java EE, sql, oracle, clear case, clear quest, Apache.

Tools: eclipse, clear case.

March 2008 to May 2008 Employer: Accenture.
Role: Software developer.
Projects: FIAT auto portal.

Responsibilities:

• Personally fixed bugs and implemented improvement features using Java, J2EE, javascript and asp on a large scale project.

Technologies: java EE, javascript, asp, html, css, jboss.

Tools: eclipse, clear case.

January 2008 to March 2008 Employer: Accenture. Role: Software developer. Projects: Mediobanca.

Responsibilities:

Write automation test for the new portal.

 Coaching to the other members of the team how to write automated test.

Technologies: java, junit.
Tools: eclipse, clear case.

INDEPENDENT PROJECTS

Web Application developed by me: (included in Facebook start program)

- Facebook Drive: Facebook Drive is a personal cloud storage service that lets users store and synchronize digital content across computers, laptops and mobile devices, and share it with their facebook friends. (javascript, marionette, nodejs, MSDN rest api, backbone, grount, bower, html5, css3, less, parse, heroku)
 - https://apps.facebook.com/drivefb/

Library developed by me:

- Easy facebook android sdk , open source library to connect android to facebook . (java, android)
 - o www.easyfacebookandroidsdk.com

Android App developed by me:

- Easy Paint: paint. (java, android, asp, php)
 - https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.easy. paint
- Face off Movie: photo app. (java, android)
 - https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.face.o ff.movie.free
- Rage Meme Camera : photo app (java , android)
 - https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.troll.fa ce&feature=more from developer
- Marble Boing 3D : game App (java, android, unity)
 - https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.gem. marbleboingfree
- Dice & Dragons 3D : dice simulation App (java, android, unity)
 - https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.gem. dicedragon
- Android Paper: rss feed reader (Easy Facebook api, java, android)
 - https://market.android.com/details?id=com.rss.androidpa per

- Real Football Italy: photo app. (java, android)
 - https://market.android.com/details?id=com.soccer.player .italy

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue Italian

Other languages English

Written: Good level Spoken: Good level